

PROFILE

10 years of a successful career managing marketing lifecycle. I bring a mix of creativity, communication, and data driven approach to generate quantifiable growth. I have scaled campaigns from zero to an ROI of 4% with an incredible growth rate of over 100%.

Working across various large corporations and startups, I am a highly organised individual and I take pride at solving complex issues with my ability to strategise and create smooth processes.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91-9820305437

EMAIL:

Jabeen.sheikh090@gmail.com

ADDRESS:

Thakur Village, Mumbai 400101

HOBBIES

- English Literature
- Reading and Writing
- Theatre
- Travel
- Animal Welfare
- Hiking
- Fitness

JABEEN SHEIKH

Brand Strategy | Marketing Communication | Digital Marketing | Product Marketing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kross Games – Marketing Manager Oct 2022 – Present

- Managing end to end communication and go to market strategy for the launch of a new gaming product
- Responsible for ideating on new product developments and liaison with the South Korean team for design, product collaterals and other communication pieces for paid & organic marketing

Tata Digital – Brand Manager

Jan 2022 – Jun 2022

- Strategising product communication for the super app
 TataNeu during launch and post launch
- Collaborating with multiple stakeholders like designers, writers, agencies, freelancers and HTML developers for various marketing and advertising campaigns
- Ideation on TVCs for the app launch during IPL for both paid and organic channels
- Market research for creating brand aesthetics and brand book

Junglee Games – Marketing Manager

Nov 2020 - Oct 2021

- Ownership of marketing and communication strategy for three products – *Howzat*, *Solitaire Gold* and *Junglee Rummy*
- Increased acquisition rates by 100% with creative branding strategies for digital marketing campaigns, PR and Influencer marketing

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Directed a Shakespearean play for the Drama Club in college

Participated & won in debates, elocutions and other competitions

Actively contributed towards animal welfare

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

MICA, Ahmedabad Advertising & PR, 2017-18

Bachelor of Arts English literature & Political science, 2010-13

St. Joseph's High School SSC – 2006

SKILLS

- Brand Management
- Marketing Communication
- Content Marketing
- Digital Marketing
- Product Marketing
- Product Management
- Advertising and PR
- ATL Marketing
- BTL Marketing

SOFT SKILLS

- Creativity
- Analytical Mindset
- Time Management
- Problem Solving
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Networking
- Customer Centric Approach
- Market Research
- Attention to Detail

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Boosted brand awareness by 200% using creative tools such as unique testimonials, ad films, and influential brand ambassadors such as Yuvraj Singh and Irfan Pathan
- Proficiently met KPI with campaigning metrics such as LTV, CAC and ROI and creative ATL marketing, BTL marketing and AB experiments
- Increased traffic by 60% and conversion by 10% using paid marketing brand strategies such as Google Ads, SEO, Affiliates, Refer A Friend and Media Planning

Games 24X7 – Associate Brand Manager May 2015 – Nov 2020

- Developed brand identity for fantasy sports product *My11Circle*; distinctive graphic style and tone for communication channels for player acquisition
- Ideation, creation and timely delivery of advertising copies, banner graphics & video ads to maximise the effectiveness of media collaterals across all platforms
- Strategised paid and organic social media activities, Google Search & Display Ads, SEO, Media Affiliates, Influencers and PR
- Identified avenues for sustainable and profitable growth for product and brand visibility leading to growth with every cricket/football series using SEO, pixel-based tracking systems and UTM parameters
- Exceeded targets in terms of player acquisition and player retention by 30% month on month.
- Conceptualised, liaised with production houses and agencies for creative collaterals such as ad films and testimonial videos
- Introduced concept of GIF creatives for multiple callouts which performed & generated ROI of 6.74%
- Onboarded brand ambassadors like Sourav Ganguly, Shane Watson & Rashid Khan
- Improved email open rates by 0.15% and click rates by 1.89%, boosted logins through off-site comms.
- Conceptualised communication & content for all collaterals that improvised player retention
- Ideated and executed branded content marketing campaigns, which increased reactivation by 15%

Mint Designs – Content Writer

Jun 2013 - Mar 2015

 SEO, long and short-form blogs & websites, create and align corporate communication plans to drive business and ROI.